<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-01T14:11:13+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/</id><title type="html">Recipes</title><subtitle>Food blog template for Jekyll.</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Pork Dumplings</title><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/2018/09/01/pork-dumplings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pork Dumplings" /><published>2018-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/2018/09/01/pork-dumplings</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/2018/09/01/pork-dumplings/">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;date: 2018-09-01
title: Pork dumplings
person: Mir en Von
categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asian&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Main Course&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Side course&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pork
image: dumplings_only.jpg
recipe:
  servings: “60-70 dumplings”
  prep: 30 minutes
  cook: 60 minutes
  ingredients: |-
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1 package round dumpling/wonton/gyoza wrappers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1 medium head nappa cabbage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1 pound ground pork&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1 bunch scallions, thinly sliced&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1 bunch cilantro, minced&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2 inch piece fresh ginger, finely grated&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2 eggs, whisked
Directions: |-
&lt;strong&gt;Prep&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Slice the cabbage and mix with salt: Slice the half-head of cabbage down its length, through the root, to make 2 quarters. Then slice each quarter into very thin strips, cutting cross-wise. Toss the slices with the salt in a large mixing bowl and set aside for 5 to 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Squeeze the liquid from the cabbage. While it rests with the salt, the cabbage will start to release liquid. When it’s ready, grab handfuls of the cabbage and squeeze out the water. Transfer the squeezed cabbage to another mixing bowl.Combine the cabbage with the rest of the filling ingredients: To the bowl with the squeezed cabbage, add the ground pork, sliced scallions, cilantro, soy sauce, ginger, sesame oil, and eggs. Work the mixture together with your hands until fully combined.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Combine the cabbage with the rest of the filling ingredients. To the bowl with the squeezed cabbage, add the ground pork, sliced scallions, cilantro, soy sauce, ginger, sesame oil, and eggs. Work the mixture together with your hands until fully combined.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Arrange your dumpling-making station. Clear a large space on the counter. Set a small bowl of water, the bowl of filling, and a parchment-lined baking sheet nearby. Open the package of dumpling wrappers and arrange a few on the work space in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Place 1 scant tablespoon of filling on each dumpling wrapper. It doesn’t look like much filling, but using any more gets messy and makes the dumplings hard to pleat closed! Once you get the hang of pleating the dumplings, you can try adding a bit more.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Dampen the edge of the wrapper with water. Dip your finger in the bowl of water and run it around the edge of the dumpling. This will help it to seal closed.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Fold the dumpling in half. Lift the dumpling from the work surface and fold it in half. Press the top closed.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Make a pleat in either side. Use your opposite thumbs to fold a tiny pleat on either side of the dumpling, then press firmly to seal the dumpling closed. You may need to dab a little water under the pleat to make it stick closed.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Repeat with all the wrappers and filling. Continue filling and pleating the rest of the wrappers using the remaining filling — this is where having a few extra hands comes in handy! As you finish each dumpling, line it up on the parchment-lined baking sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cooking&lt;/strong&gt;
    1. Film a skillet with about a tablespoon of oil and warm over high heat. When the oil is shimmering, arrange the dumplings in the pan as close as they’ll fit without actually touching. Cook until the bottoms have turned brown and golden.
    2. Pour 3 tablespoons of water in the pan — the water will immediately sizzle and begin to steam.
    3. Cover the pan immediately and reduce the heat to low. (If your skillet doesn’t have a lid, cover with a baking sheet.)
    4. Cook the dumplings for 3 to 5 minutes if fresh, or 6 to 8 minutes if frozen. When done, the wrappers will appear translucent and noodle-like; the filling will be opaque and warmed through (you can cut one open to check).
    5. Transfer the cooked dumplings to a plate and serve with soy sauce or other dipping sauce.
 —&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/recipes/images/recipes/dumpling.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;recipe prep&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">date: 2018-09-01 title: Pork dumplings person: Mir en Von categories: Asian Main Course Side course Pork image: dumplings_only.jpg recipe: servings: “60-70 dumplings” prep: 30 minutes cook: 60 minutes ingredients: |- 1 package round dumpling/wonton/gyoza wrappers 1 medium head nappa cabbage 1 pound ground pork 1 bunch scallions, thinly sliced 1 bunch cilantro, minced 2 inch piece fresh ginger, finely grated 2 tablespoons sesame oil 3 tablespoons soy sauce 1 tablespoon salt 2 eggs, whisked Directions: |- Prep Slice the cabbage and mix with salt: Slice the half-head of cabbage down its length, through the root, to make 2 quarters. Then slice each quarter into very thin strips, cutting cross-wise. Toss the slices with the salt in a large mixing bowl and set aside for 5 to 10 minutes. Squeeze the liquid from the cabbage. While it rests with the salt, the cabbage will start to release liquid. When it’s ready, grab handfuls of the cabbage and squeeze out the water. Transfer the squeezed cabbage to another mixing bowl.Combine the cabbage with the rest of the filling ingredients: To the bowl with the squeezed cabbage, add the ground pork, sliced scallions, cilantro, soy sauce, ginger, sesame oil, and eggs. Work the mixture together with your hands until fully combined. Combine the cabbage with the rest of the filling ingredients. To the bowl with the squeezed cabbage, add the ground pork, sliced scallions, cilantro, soy sauce, ginger, sesame oil, and eggs. Work the mixture together with your hands until fully combined. Arrange your dumpling-making station. Clear a large space on the counter. Set a small bowl of water, the bowl of filling, and a parchment-lined baking sheet nearby. Open the package of dumpling wrappers and arrange a few on the work space in front of you. Place 1 scant tablespoon of filling on each dumpling wrapper. It doesn’t look like much filling, but using any more gets messy and makes the dumplings hard to pleat closed! Once you get the hang of pleating the dumplings, you can try adding a bit more. Dampen the edge of the wrapper with water. Dip your finger in the bowl of water and run it around the edge of the dumpling. This will help it to seal closed. Fold the dumpling in half. Lift the dumpling from the work surface and fold it in half. Press the top closed. Make a pleat in either side. Use your opposite thumbs to fold a tiny pleat on either side of the dumpling, then press firmly to seal the dumpling closed. You may need to dab a little water under the pleat to make it stick closed. Repeat with all the wrappers and filling. Continue filling and pleating the rest of the wrappers using the remaining filling — this is where having a few extra hands comes in handy! As you finish each dumpling, line it up on the parchment-lined baking sheet. Cooking 1. Film a skillet with about a tablespoon of oil and warm over high heat. When the oil is shimmering, arrange the dumplings in the pan as close as they’ll fit without actually touching. Cook until the bottoms have turned brown and golden. 2. Pour 3 tablespoons of water in the pan — the water will immediately sizzle and begin to steam. 3. Cover the pan immediately and reduce the heat to low. (If your skillet doesn’t have a lid, cover with a baking sheet.) 4. Cook the dumplings for 3 to 5 minutes if fresh, or 6 to 8 minutes if frozen. When done, the wrappers will appear translucent and noodle-like; the filling will be opaque and warmed through (you can cut one open to check). 5. Transfer the cooked dumplings to a plate and serve with soy sauce or other dipping sauce. —</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zomerpasta</title><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/pasta/main%20course/vegetarian/2018/08/26/zomerpasta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zomerpasta" /><published>2018-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/pasta/main%20course/vegetarian/2018/08/26/zomerpasta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/pasta/main%20course/vegetarian/2018/08/26/zomerpasta/">&lt;p&gt;Also great the next day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Also great the next day!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/zomerpasta.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blue Cheese and Walnut Pasta</title><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/pasta/main%20course/vegetarian/2018/08/26/bluecheese-walnut-pasta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blue Cheese and Walnut Pasta" /><published>2018-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/pasta/main%20course/vegetarian/2018/08/26/bluecheese-walnut-pasta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/pasta/main%20course/vegetarian/2018/08/26/bluecheese-walnut-pasta/">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Vapiano&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/recipes/images/recipes/bluecheese_walnut_prep.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;recipe prep&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Inspired by Vapiano</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/bluecheese_walnut.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pumpkin Curry</title><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/curry/vegetarian/main%20course/slowcooker/2017/11/05/pumpkin-curry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pumpkin Curry" /><published>2017-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/curry/vegetarian/main%20course/slowcooker/2017/11/05/pumpkin-curry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/curry/vegetarian/main%20course/slowcooker/2017/11/05/pumpkin-curry/">&lt;p&gt;Uit de volkskrant, lekker met naan!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Uit de volkskrant, lekker met naan!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/pumpkin-curry-small.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wendy’s Quiche Lorraine</title><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/snacks/2017/10/22/quiche-wendy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wendy's Quiche Lorraine" /><published>2017-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/snacks/2017/10/22/quiche-wendy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/snacks/2017/10/22/quiche-wendy/">&lt;p&gt;Yum!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Yum!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/quiche.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chocolate Cupcakes</title><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/desserts/2017/01/07/chocolate-cupcakes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chocolate Cupcakes" /><published>2017-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/desserts/2017/01/07/chocolate-cupcakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/desserts/2017/01/07/chocolate-cupcakes/">&lt;p&gt;These chocolate chocolate cupcakes have a stunning appearance and a rich, chocolatey sweetness. I’ve found at parties people prefer bite sized deserts so I’d recommend making 24 mini cupcakes rather than 12 large. That way you won’t find half eaten cupcakes at your party!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1448131063153-f1e240f98a72?w=1560&amp;amp;h=940&amp;amp;fit=crop&quot; alt=&quot;Cupcakes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can never go wrong with sprinkles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1420730614543-e39f93134b0d?w=1560&amp;amp;h=940&amp;amp;fit=crop&quot; alt=&quot;Cupcakes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milk is a great addition to any cupcake experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1457508252818-162dc1934c2f?w=1560&amp;amp;h=940&amp;amp;fit=crop&quot; alt=&quot;Cupcakes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not add some popcorn?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">These chocolate chocolate cupcakes have a stunning appearance and a rich, chocolatey sweetness. I’ve found at parties people prefer bite sized deserts so I’d recommend making 24 mini cupcakes rather than 12 large. That way you won’t find half eaten cupcakes at your party!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://source.unsplash.com/qJ0zGkrE1Zg/1560x940" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lemon Cake</title><link href="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/desserts/2017/01/06/lemon-cake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lemon Cake" /><published>2017-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/desserts/2017/01/06/lemon-cake</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shiltemann.github.io/recipes/desserts/2017/01/06/lemon-cake/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re a sour fan you’re going to love this cake. Lemon Cake is one of my favorite year-round desserts, but it is a perfect choice for spring and summer, when everyone tends to crave citrus or light &amp;amp; flavorful recipes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/1HPTYLozDGw&quot; alt=&quot;Cake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straight out of the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/WoVGndRTx2o&quot; alt=&quot;Cake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add extra flavour with berries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/7JYVKRo7i5Q&quot; alt=&quot;Cake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or a caramel sauce.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">If you’re a sour fan you’re going to love this cake. Lemon Cake is one of my favorite year-round desserts, but it is a perfect choice for spring and summer, when everyone tends to crave citrus or light &amp;amp; flavorful recipes</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://source.unsplash.com/NAN22eh754c/1560x940" /></entry></feed>